Previously on Dating Alys Perez.
What did you do?!
Fier is pregnant!
You can't be with Alys!
Alys...
Just go, Drake. Leave me alone!
Alys, wait!
- I said, leave!
- Alys!
- Can't you understand?
- Alys, I love you, not Fier.
You freaking banged me
and you’re telling me
you don’t want to take responsibility?
Fier, I won’t run away from you.
Drake Sebastian Jimenez Palma...
Will you please marry this selfish girl?
Mom, Dad,
I have something to say.
Drake and I...
We're getting married.
I'm sorry, Alys. But you can't.
Alys,
you can't marry him.
But why, Dad? Give me a reason!
Alys!
Don't shout at your Dad.
How can I not shout at him?! I’m —
Alys.
Calm down.
How can I calm down?
Why can't we get married?
Because Drake is having a
baby with someone else!
What in that sentence
can't you understand?
Auntie...
Drake,
you just can't.
Oh, come on, Mom!
Don't be such a freakin' hypocrite!
Dad accepted you even when
you had a child that wasn’t his.
Why can’t —
Alys,
I'm sorry.
Drake.
Do you really love my daughter?
Yes, Uncle.
That’s the only thing I’m certain
about in my life right now.
And...
what happened between
you and the girl?
Alys, please.
Please!
I can't do this right now, Mom.
I’m not in the right headspace.
What are you doing, Alys?
It’s all just too painful for me.
It hurts my brain,
my heart and my soul!
I feel like I'm being beaten up!
Alys, please.
I didn't want to break down,
but things just pushed me to.
What are you doing, Alys?
I'm running away!
Are you sure?
It was just one time?
That was...
That was lapse of
judgment on my part, Uncle.
Alys and I had
broken up at that time.
I thought we’d never
get back together.
But then I realized, that Alys
was the only one for me.
And if it’s not her,
then I’d rather be alone.
I really,
really love your daughter, Uncle.
She’s the only one I’ve ever loved,
and the only one I ever will.
Just make sure you sort things out.
It may be hard now.
But eventually,
everything will be okay.
I hope so, Uncle.
Alys.
Drake!
Are you leaving Mommy?
Go.
Thank you.
- Alys.
- Drake!
Come on, let's go!
Drake, let's go.
We're running away.
You don't wanna run
away with me, don't you?
Alys,
running away is not a solution.
If you’re not going to be with
me through this, then leave.
Alys, Alys!
Leave, Drake!
Leave me alone, Drake!
Just go!
Leave, Drake! Leave!
Leave! I said, leave!
I said, leave!
Leave me alone!
Tripp...
Alys?
Are you crying again?
Where are you?
Can I please go there?
Please?
You shouldn’t leave in that state, Zy.
I'll go to you.
Where are you?
No.
No, Tripp listen to me.
I can't.
I can't stay here any longer.
I feel like...
I feel like my sanity would
just fly out of the window.
I can't stay here any longer.
Please, Tripp...
Please!
Can I just go there?
Please help me.
Okay.
I hear you.
I'll just send you the address.
And I'll pick you up.
Okay?
Thank you, Tripp.
Okay.
Ugh, seriously.
Unbelievable.
I never learn.
It’s still about him.
You love him, right?
So much.
Too much.
Giving up is hard, Zy.
So hard.
Especially me, I know.
If I hadn't given up,
you'd be with me instead.
You know what, Zy?
Honestly,
I don't know what I can
do to make you feel better.
Tripp, it really hurts.
Come here.
Maybe we’d be happy
and at peace right now,
if he were the one I loved so deeply.
I just know that he wouldn't hurt me.
You know, Zy.
He would hurt you,
but it'll be worth it.
That's how it goes, Zy.
When it comes to the person you love,
no matter how painful,
no matter how long it takes,
it'll all be worth it in the end.
Here.
Come on.
Go eat.
Your fries,
and your burger.
Thank you.
You know,
you've always been like this.
I need to remind you before you eat.
You’re so harsh with me.
I do eat on my own sometimes.
Remember Brenford?
The park where we used to hang out?
Yes.
You always had your camera with you.
What happened to that?
Well...
my dreams were swept away,
the moment I entered the real world.
Happens to everyone, doesn't it?
Dreams change as we grow older.
Replaced by new ones.
But there’s one dream
that never changed.
What?
I think the question should be...
who?
Tripp.
Hmm?
If I ask you
to run away with me,
would you?
You know what,
just finish your dinner, Zy.
You’re thinking of all sorts of things.
Look,
you haven't touched it the
whole time we were here.
Are you eating like a bird?
Eat first.
Then I'll take you home.
But I don't wanna go home.
I told you, I don't wanna be there.
Please, Tripp.
I don't wanna go home.
- Tripp!
- Zy.
- Zy...
- Please?
Running away won't do anything good.
Trust me.
It hurts knowing you're choosing me again.
Not because you truly want me,
but because things between you
and Drake aren't working out.
Again.
My body’s exhausted,
but my mind is wide awake.
It wouldn't let me sleep.
And the worst part is,
it’s even harder to think when
your mind is filled
with painful thoughts.
Good thing I don't
have any plans today.
I mean, I have work but...
I don’t want to deal with it yet.
I just want to run, escape and breathe.
Whatever.
Alys.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Are you mad at me?
No.
Where were you last night?
With Tripp.
I almost asked him to
run away with me, you know.
But you didn't.
Yeah, I didn't.
I promised you I
wouldn't leave you, right?
Just marry me already, Drake.
I’m losing my mind here.
I’m about to snap.
Yes, Alys.
I will marry you.
Thank you.
Let them be angry.
Even your mom and dad.
But yes.
We will get married.
Is this the start of
our happily ever after?
I hope so.
Alys...
Zyril...
Perez.
Hmm?
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Love is patient.
Love is kind.
Drake Palma!
You're my boyfriend now!
It does not envy.
It does not boast.
I'm Alys.
Alys Zyril Perez.
Soon to be Palma.
Hello!
It is not proud.
It is not self-seeking.
It is not easily angered.
It keeps no record of wrongs.
Love does not delight in evil.
But rejoices with the truth.
I'm territorial.
It always protects.
It always trusts.
It always hopes.
It always perseveres.
Love never fails.
And by the authority vested in me
by Article 7, Paragraph 1 of the
Family Code of the Philippines.
Calling all those present
here as witnesses,
Patrick Sanchez and Gail Cortez.
I now pronounce you
man and wife.
You may now kiss the bride.
Hey, take it easy.
It's not your honeymoon yet.
I’m sorry.
- Thank you, bro.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
What?
Nothing.
I just can't believe we're finally married!
For heaven's sake!
Are you happy, Alys?
Words can't suffice how
I'm feeling right now.
But yes,
I'm very, very much happy.
Good to know.
Because I'm very happy, too.
Even if it's not your dream wedding, Alys.
I promise you, I'll give you
that dream wedding soon.
Oh, come on.
Even if it's just a civil wedding,
we're still married.
And that's what's important.
So, where are we going?
To forever.
This might be the happiest day of my life.
Drake, why are we here?
Drake, what are we doing here?
Drake, seriously, why are we here?
I’ll introduce you to them.
Your family already knows me,
Drake Sebastian Palma.
They know you as Alys – my girlfriend,
as Alys – my heartbreaker,
as Alys – I've been
chasing for all these years.
So what do you mean?
I'm introducing you
as Alys Zyril
Palma.
My wife.
Ready?
But,
I'm nervous.
Me too.
We can do this.
Come on, we've been through worse.
I'm sure we can get through this.
Let's go?
Let's go, Drake.
Wait.
OMG, is this for real?
Let’s go.
Answer me, Alys!
Why is she not picking up?
I wonder if Alys’s message is true.
Or was it a prank?
Why would she even marry Drake?
Is she insane?
- Who got married?
- Oh god.
Oh, Auntie...
our client!
M-miss... Alonzo!
- Okay, and what about her?
- She got married.
She just messaged us,
to say thank you.
Because we did her wedding gown.
Aww, that's so sweet.
Well, tell her thank you
for supporting us, okay?
Yes, Auntie. I'll pass it along.
Alright.
Wow!
That's sweet of Uncle Andy!
A bouquet of flowers!
Oh no, this isn't from him
and this isn't for me!
It's for you.
For me?
Yeah!
Anyway, let me check
the status of your sketch.
Here, Auntie.
Okay.
Alright, I'll be back later, okay?
Thank you!
Thank you.
I still miss you, Bee.
Let’s make up.
Honey?
So what do you want
me to do now, Fier?
Stay here. I'll be back for you.
So, the jerk is here.
You loser! How dare you?!
Dad, Dad!
Dad, I didn't give you his name
so you could start a fight!
I thought we're here to talk.
Shut up, Fier!
I didn't raise you to be
pregnant and unwed!
- But, Dad!
- I said shut up!
And you, Palma...
You better marry my daughter.
If you don’t want to see me get angry.
Mr. Sandoval, please!
We can resolve this calmly.
Let’s fix this. Let's settle this.
Mr. Palma,
as a father I won't let my daughter
be knocked up and derailed like this.
I understand.
What do you want?
How can we resolve this?
I want for your son to marry my daughter.
Drake.
No, Dad.
- What?!
- Dad, stop! Dad.
Stop, stop. Dad, please.
Mr. Sandoval, please.
I can't let you scold my
son inside our own house.
Let's settle this peacefully.
Fine, talk to your son.
Drake, won't you reconsider?
No, Dad.
I refuse.
Not now,
not ever.
- You asshole!
- Dad, Dad, please!
- Dad, please!
- Dad, Dad!
He doesn't love me.
And I also don't wanna push myself.
So please, let's just go home.
She's right, Dad. Don't push it.
Shut up, Lourd!
I’m not talking to you!
Don't interfere.
You're getting married.
And you'll do what I say!
If he won't marry you,
then you're not coming home.
I'll cut all your resources!
You'll have to stay here,
until this jerk marries you!
What?!
Let's go.
Lourd, Chance.
One more thing, Mr. Palma.
The next time we meet,
I hope it will be a pleasant one.
Dad, wait. Don't leave me here!
Dad, wait!
Dad, are you really leaving Fier behind?
Yes, it's her fault for getting knocked up.
But Dad...
The two of you, get it together.
You don't want to see me get angry, too.
As for me, I'm always protected.
Asshole!
What? I didn't do anything.
Both of you shut up. Let's go.
I'll leave you two alone to talk.
Should I go up to Drake?
What do I do?
I thought I've been through the worst.
I didn't know things
could get even worse.
Drake,
you can't push me away.
I'm pregnant.
I don't want to live on the street.
Fine.
Thank you.
But I won't marry you, Fier.
I know.
But don't plan for the ending yet.
We'll be living under one roof.
You have no idea what could happen.
I'm married, Fier.
I married Alys earlier.
You asshole!
You're crazy.
Crazy in love.
Even before.
I heard everything.
Don't worry, Alys.
I'll take care of everything.
But for now,
the fact remains,
we’re married and there’s nothing
they can do about it anymore.
So what's the plan?
I thought you heard everything?
No, I mean...
What do I do now?
So much has happened today.
We got married without my family knowing.
I can't just go back home and
pretend like nothing happened.
You know that my family's
against our wedding.
Live with me.
What?
Alys,
I said live with me.
We're married.
And I want us to be together.
What about Fier?
She'll have nowhere to stay.
Her father disowned her.
She can stay here.
She just needs a place for now.
So...
we'll both live under one roof?
All three of us?
Physically, yes.
But, emotionally?
It'll just be the two of us.
I don't know, Drake.
Actually, I don't know if
anything's right about this.
Neither do I, Alys.
All I know is I love you so much.
We're married now.
But I have a responsibility to Fier.
And this is the only thing
that I could think of
for the both of you.
This is unfair to Alys.
But this is also unfair to Fier.
But what can I do?
There's no other option.
I can't abandon my wife.
But I have to do right by my child.
When will this end?
This chaos.
So, after this wedding,
what's next?
What about Fier?
What about the baby?
What else will I have to face with Drake?
When will our trials end?
Until when will destiny keep testing us?
I know all is fair in love and war.
When it comes to my cousin,
you're so weak, Alys.
Ouch! That hurts.
Good for you then!
Because you’re an expert
when it comes to love, right?
That’s why you don’t have a girlfriend!
Come on.
Why is this suddenly about me?
What we’re talking about here
is your craziness, Alys.
You should know that.
Listen.
You've been staying at
Drake's for three days
living with that Fier.
Does that sound sane to you?
God, that's peak!
Okay, look. I know the idea was crazy.
But I'm even crazier!
And honestly, never once in my life
did I ever consider doing
something like this.
But I still managed to do it.
- Oh lord!
- So you are self-aware!
And Fier's not even helping.
She's such a bitch, you know!
What?
You expect her to be nice to you?
Hello!
That's enough, Tofer!
I can't even sleep at night!
The nights are the most stressful.
I'm about to call the OB.
Fine, I get it.
She's acting like a lunatic
because she's pregnant.
But that doesn't excuse it.
She's pregnant not a psycho.
Fine, Alys.
Let’s talk this through properly.
Alys, what the hell?
What the hell?
Yes!
I know you and Drake are married.
But how did you get yourself
stuck in that house with that —
Excuse me for the term...
Mistress!
Hey, that's too much.
I really don't like it when
people call Fier a mistress.
It hurts. For her and for me.
I mean, it's hard to even force
myself to be angry at her.
I always remember that
she carries Drake's child.
That fact alone is
enough to pacify my heart.
The fact is, that's what she is.
No matter how you look at this,
you're married to Drake.
It hurts to be called a mistress.
And it's not her fault that Drake's
not planning on marrying her.
It's not Drake's fault either.
In fact, it's no one's fault.
We're all just victims of fate.
The timing is just so screwed up.
What do you mean it
wasn't Drake's fault?
He created all of this mess!
Hey, Tofer!
I know you like Tripp over him but
don't take it all out on Drake.
Actually,
he did offer his unit, I just declined.
There it is!
Alys Zyril Perez,
why do you have to
stick yourself in that house
when you have the choice not to?
Why do I want to be there?
I don't know.
Maybe it's because I don't want
Drake to go through this alone.
I don't want him to have to choose.
Four years of struggle is enough.
Hey, Tofer,
I came here to relax,
not be scolded by you.
I just came from Aya's sermons,
I don't need yours too.
I asked you to come so I could vent.
Not so you could be my parent.
Annoying.
Fine.
Bestie has gone crazy.
What do I have to do
to get through to her?
S...
O...
R, R...
Y?
Sorry?
Bee! Sorry!
Damn it, Kent.
Did I startle you, Bee?
Isn't it obvious?
Sorry, sorry for everything, Bee.
For startling you,
for being so clingy.
Believe me,
I've learned my lesson!
Geez!
You came just to say sorry?
Is that really all?
You could have just sent a message.
Bee, of course not.
I'm ready to win you back.
Bee, forgive me, please!
Whatever you want, I'll do it.
Let me make it up to you!
We've been apart for so long.
It's driving me insane, Bee!
No, no, get up!
I don't want you to go insane!
It’s enough that I just know
one crazy person.
What? Who?
Whatever, just stand up,
or I won't forgive you!
See? That wasn't hard.
Bee...
Come on, Bee.
I just want us to be back together.
If I forgive this idiot,
does that make me as crazy as Alys?
Probably not.
It's entirely different.
Only if...
you'll court me again.
Huh?
Yeah! Thank you, Bee!
Fier!
Have you eaten yet?
I brought fruits!
What game are we playing here, Alys?
Huh?
Quit acting nice.
I know you're mad at me.
Be bitchy or whatever.
I don't care.
Just quit acting like you care.
Fier...
Drop it, Alys!
You don't care.
Deep inside, you want me
and my child to disappear.
Is that right?
Come on, Fier.
Stop it, Alys.
We both know how this is going to end.
One of us has to go.
You're married to him.
And we're having a child.
Can't you see how crazy our situation is?
This baby?
This baby will be labeled a bastard, Alys.
A bastard!
Fier!
Fier, wait! Wait!
- Fier!
- Ouch!
Oh my god!
Fier! Are you okay?
Ouch!
Fier, oh my god!
What's happening?
Shut up, Alys! Ouch!
Do you want me to call a doctor?
Fier, please let me help you.
Don't touch me, Alys!
- Fier...
- Ouch!
I'm right.
This is gonna happen.
I really want to be a responsible
husband to Alys.
But I have to be a responsible father.
But with all of this,
all I'm thinking about is Alys.
Only Alys.
She's my world.
She's my home.
Only her.
And I know through all of this,
she'll have to bear my burdens.
Alys,
please be strong for me.
For us.
Fier is here.
I hope we face this together.
Please.
Please don't leave me.
Or else I'll break.
I need you, Alys.
I need you, my noob.
On the next episode of
Dating Alys Perez.
You can't let her be angry at Alys.
It's not good for the child.
Drake, my decision is final.
I'm leaving for now.
- Shaira!
- Alys!
You poor thing!
I'm just accommodating Fier's needs.
Because I'm pretty sure what
he's going through is not easy.
But what you're going
through is not easy too, Alys!
OMG!
I knew you were stupid,
but not to this extent!
- That's harsh.
- My god, please!
Tripp,
thank you.
You didn't leave me.
Not yet.
I still can't.
What?
Nothing.
I haven't a clue as to why
you're tolerating this bullshit!
Alys, wake up!
You're the wife!
Why did you have to leave?
Fuck it.
Hey I'm not done with
you yet, Ms. Homewrecker!
Miss Whoever-You-Are!
Watch your fucking words!
If Alys won't do anything about it,
I sure as hell will!